

Curriculum Vitae for Asmund Ødegård

Personal information

Address: Sneisveien 26 E-mail: asmund@xal.no

1407 Vinterbro Phone: +47 90 06 99 15

Born: 23.08.1972

Summary

I am a senior software developer, project leader, and researcher, with 20 years of professional experience. Most of my career prior to founding Expert Analytics AS together with Ola Skavhaug, has been with Simula Research Laboratory, ranked as Norway's best ICT research institution in 2012. Through various positions in that company I have obtained a broad set of technical and management skills, which I since 2013 has used as Managing Director and Senior Consultant in Expert Analytics. My main areas of technical expertise spans from mathematical software development and scripting, to administration of advanced ICT solutions and configuration management. Both through education and practical hands-on experience I have developed strong analytical skills within my fields of expertise.

As manager and leader of several projects with internal and external participants, I have learned the importance of understanding the strengths and skills of the participants in order to deliver on time. Communication within the team is always key to ensure that everyone have ownership in the project and stay motivated. This must always be balanced with a firm leadership.

Technical skills

Frameworks Google App Engine, AWS, Azure, Kubernetes, Numpy, Pandas

Languages Python, C++, C#, Go, C, Sql, Bash, Java, LATEX, Racket, Javascript,

Common Lisp

Tools Vim, Git, (and much more..)

Education

2006 Dr. Scient in Scientific Computing, Faculty of Mathematics and Na-

tural Sciences, University of Oslo. Thesis' title "Applications of high

level software for parallel solution of Partial Differential Equations."

1995 Cand. Scient in Applied and Industrial Mathematics, Department of

Mathematics, University of Oslo

Professional experience

2013 –	Managing Director and Consultant at Expert Analytics
2011 - 2013	Director of External Research Funding at Simula Research Laboratory
2010 - 2011	Director of Administration at Simula Research Laboratory
2008 - 2010	Assistant Director of Administration at Simula Research Laboratory
2004 - 2009	IT Manager at Simula Research Laboratory
2005 - 2007	Research Scientist at Simula Research Laboratory
2001 - 2005	Scientific Programmer at Simula Research Laboratory
2000 - 2001	Scientific Programmer at Department of Informatics, University of
	Oslo
1996 – 1999	Research Assistant at Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
1996	Summer intern, SINTEF Applied Mathematics
1993 – 1994	Assistant teacher, Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo

Languages

English Fluent

Norwegian Mother tongue

Personal skills

Communication Writing and editing, typesetting & typography

Funding EU and RCN funding instruments, consortium development, proposal

writing

Management Development and implementation of strategies, guidelines and proce-

dures, lead and encourage staff, personnel follow-up

Technology Extensive knowledge about system administration; always eager to

learn about new frameworks and open source technologies; solution

architect and problem solver

Some interests and hobbies

Hard Bicycle, motorcycle

Soft Playing clarinet and saxophone, cooking &wine, photography Tech Fonts, typesetting with TEX, computers, gadgets, coding

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Auka/mCASH development

Period 08.2013 - 05.2014, 02.2016 - 04.2017

Role Senior Python Developer

Staffing 12–15 developers

Description

I worked with mCASH, later renamed Auka, in two periods—from August 2013 until May 2014 and from February 2016 until April 2017. My responsibilities in this project included integrations of third-party APIs for user-identification with Norwegian BankID, and development of APIs for access to mCASH resources for external integrators, based on OpenID Connect and Oauth protocols. I was also deeply involved in design and implementation of the transactional engine handling the payments; the core of the mCASH system. This engine connects persons, merchants and banks together, and computes transaction fees for involved parties in addition to moving correct amounts. I was lead developer for a new settlement system for merchants. The backend system of mCASH is implemented solely in Python. I have also been involved with other parts of the code base, including javascript frontend implemented with React. The development at mCASH followed the scrum agile method.

Tools

Python, Google app engine, webapp2, Jinja2, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, Nose tests, Git, Jira.

Activity SmartBlikk development Period 06.2014 – 06.2015

Role Systems Architect and Senior Developer

Staffing 2–5 developers

Description SmartBlikk is a business intelligence solution for the SME market. My

responsibility was development of an API for the system for import of data from external systems, as well as integrating external APIs for use from SmartBlikk, mainly for importing accounting data. The pilot of SmartBlikk was created by the founder of Intelliview, and I am in charge of designing and implementing the second version of the system with dynamic in-browser reporting capabilities. I am also in charge of establishing a deployment environment for SmartBlikk on the cloud, specifically on Amazon Elastic Beanstalk scaling out with

multiple EC2 nodes and using AWS RDS database.

Tools Php, Mysql, Slim, Twig, Javascript, jQuery, AWS EB, AWS EC2, AWS

RDS.

Activity FrontSystems development

Period 01.2015 – 01.2016

Role Senior Developer and adviser

Staffing 3 developers

Description FrontSystems is a Norwegian company developing a web-based POS

system. The current system was build on some technologies that are approaching EOL, and my main role was to advise and contribute towards a more modern architecture. This include moving development and deployment to Github and Azure as well as implementing reporting services in POS backend using client-side JS rather than Microsoft

reporting services.

Tools C#, JavaScript, Asp.Net, Knockout, Bootstrap, RequireJS, jQuery,

MSSQL, TeamCity, Git, Azure.

Activity Vipps development
Period 05.2017 – 04.2020
Role Senior Consultant
Staffing 20+ developers,

Description From May 2017 until April 2020 I worked with Vipps AS. I was working

together with in-house developers and other consultants on development of core and auxillary systems. I was project manager and tech lead for systems for Merchant onboarding and some of the other projects made necessary in connection with the establishment of Vipps as a separate legal entity. From fall 2017 until spring 2019 I was also responsible for deployment and operation of Kubernetes clusters on the Azure platform, mainly used for operational services in the Merchant domain. Further, I was continuing work along the lines of earlier

mCASH development relevant in the new company.

Tools Java, Go, Azure, MSSQL, PostgreSQL

Activity Demographic and financial estimations

Period 09.2011 – 04.2012

Role Architect and main developer

Staffing Project leader, developer, front-end designer

Description For customer we developed a web-based tool for statistical estimation

of demographics within a large closed group, and a tool for economical planning of a large scale development. My main contribution was the mathematical analysis of the problem, and development of the necessary logic and algorithms. Further, I also implemented the system in a custom application server. The work was carried out in

close collaboration with financial experts and a designer.

Tools Python, Pandas, Web.py, Sqlite, MS Sql, Excel, HTML, CSS, Java-

Script, jQuery